# **ERIC PAUELTICH**

425-327-4188 epauletich@gmail.com

17510 Oak St Granite Falls, WA 98252

#### **PROFILE**

Motivated network professional with many years experience as an Network/ Systems Administrator. Accustomed to handling sensitive, confidential records in a professional manner. Flexible and versatile, I am able to maintain a sense of humor under pressure. Poised and competent with a demonstrated ability to easily transcend cultural differences. I thrive in any environment, to include hectic and fast paced environments.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# Systems Administrator, Seattle Lighting — 9/2019 - 2/2020

Maintained the small network that utilizes Cisco switches, virtual linux/ windows servers and workstations. Troubleshooting connectivity issues as well as maintaining network and server up time. Using Manage-engine suite of products for remote help, Mobile device Management, as well as improving connectivity throughout the building. Working with Windows server 2008 R2, and Windows 7 pro to Windows 10 Pro upgrades. Maintained Hyper-V and VMWare ESXi 5.5 for more stable virtual environment. Exchange, Apache, Active Directory, with Remote Desktop Remote App services. Daily tasks of not just helping the users or being in one location but though all the stores in the Seattle area, Portland area and Dallas. Even went to help get the Dallas store back online after a tornado hit and destroyed the showroom floor.

## Systems Administrator, Mitchell MCN — 1/2019 - 6/2019

Maintained, configured and fixed Computer networks to include application troubleshooting and printer upkeep. Most networks managed used Cisco Meraki. With a VPN connection to backups in Azure. Using tools from LanSweeper, Tenable, and Solarwinds. Started to use Carbon Black anti virus for a better AV control over all devices, whether they were onsite or offsite. Used Intune and Azure Active Directory for user logins that were not onsite with the domain controller. Using Connect Wise and Jira to handle Helpdesk tickets with the Help Desk engineer, with the many things he could not take care of. The biggest task from day to day was making sure users in the 2016 Remote Desktop Services can login over the SD-WAN or remotely to be able to their jobs. Used nutanix and migrated all the VM from the old hardware to the new converged environment, in a High available VMware Hyperconverged environment.

# **ERIC PAUELTICH**

## Sr. IT Technician, Black Label IT LLC — 8/2018 - 11/2018

Maintained, configured and fixed Computer networks to include application troubleshooting and printer upkeep. Most networks managed used Cisco, Dell, Switches, Meraki. Managed WiFi using an Unifi Controller in Azure and Meraki in the Cloud. Using tools from Sophos Central to N-Central for monitoring, patching, Anti-Virus for local and remote device management, to include MSP Manager for Ticketing and keeping track of billable time. Upgrading Customers individual PC's backup using Shadow protect to ensure that there was many ways to recover the data. Doing many projects from Network switch replacement to desktop hardware refresh.

## IT Technician, Smooth-IT — 9/2015 - 7/2018

Maintained, configured and fixed Computer networks to include application troubleshooting and printer upkeep. Most networks managed used Cisco, Dell, Ubiquiti Switches, both Unifi and EdgeMax. Managed WiFi using an Unifi Controller in Azure. A customer also used Unifi Video Camera's for the security, easy setup and maintenance. Using tools from N-Central for monitoring, patching, Anti-Virus for local and remote device management, to include Autotask for Ticketing and keeping track of billable time. Upgrading Customers from Windows 7 to Windows 10 Pro, Server 2008R2 to Server 2016 using FOG server, Windows Imaging, made redundant backup using Windows backup and Azure to ensure that there was many ways to recover that data. Doing many projects from Network switch replacement to desktop hardware refresh.

## Network/Systems Administrator, Comtronic Systems — 6/2014 - 12/2014

Maintained the small network that utilizes Cisco switches, virtual linux/ windows servers and workstations. Troubleshooting connectivity issues as well as maintaining network and server up time. Building new servers and desktops from hardware and cleaning out the old inventory. While there I also made an inventory program to track the many different network assets and who they were assigned to. Configuring Firewall for fiber network, as well as improving connectivity throughout the building. Working with Windows server 2008 R2 through server 2012 R2, and Windows 7 pro to Windows 8.1 Pro upgrades. Implemented VMWare ESXi 5.5 for more stable virtual environment. Exchange, Apache, Active Directory, with Remote Desktop Remote App services.

# **ERIC PAUELTICH**

## TIER III INCIDENT ENGINEER, MICROSOFT — 10/2011 - 1/2013

Troubleshooting server problems in the Production and Preproduction environments throughout multiple datacenters across the world. Working with many different teams via IM and Voice chat to resolve issues that require more support. Resolved many networking and connectivity problems within the environment. Working with Windows Server 2003/2008 environment, fielding many different customer requests in Exchange, IIS, and Active Directory, restoring Blackberry Services, troubleshooting problems within exchange, SQL, and other customer issues with the service. Helping the lead on duty by training new personnel, being the go-to guy answering questions and assisting other Engineers.

### **EDUCATION**

Renton Technical College, Renton, WA — AAS-T, 2011

#### **SKILLS**

- Windows Servers
- •Windows 7, 8, 10
- •Linux
- MacOS
- Networking
- Carbon Black AV
- •VMware ESXiHyper-V
- •Visual Basic Script/ Applications
- •Software Defined Networking (Meraki and UniFi)

- •PC Computer Maintenance
- •Cloud Computing
- •Virtualization Hyper-v, ESXi
- Basic Cisco Router setup
- •Edgerouter Setup
- LAN Design

- Adobe Acrobat
- Professional

Presentations

- Written
- Correspondence
- •Records Management
- •Sensitive Document

Management

- •Leadership Training
- •Relationship Building
- General Office Skills

### **CERTIFICATIONS**

COMPTIA A+ — 5/2011 MICROSOFT CERTIFIED PROFESSIONAL — 1/2017 APPLE CERTIFIED ASSOCIATE — 2/2017

### **MILITARY SERVICE**

UNITED STATES MARINE CORPS — 8/2003 - 11/2010 HONORABLE DISCHARGE, ACTIVE DUTY